♪
( crowd murmuring )
( Kirito sighs )
Liena: KIRITO.
Kirito: EH?
YEAH, LIENA?
LISTEN. I HAVE FAITH
IN YOUR SKILLS AS A SWORDSMAN,
BUT I HAVE TO WARN YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING.
( Kirito sighs )
Liena: THE LEVANTEINS
HAVE A SAYING
HANDED DOWN FOR GENERATIONS.
"SOAK YOUR SWORD
IN THE BLOOD OF THE MIGHTY,
AND YOU WILL MAKE
THEIR STRENGTH BECOME YOUR OWN."
Kirito: LIKE "BLOOD" BLOOD?
Liena: YES.
BEFORE HE STARTED HERE,
VOLO HAD BEEN ENGAGING
IN FIRST-STRIKE DUELS
WITH REAL SWORDS FOR A WHILE.
AS A RESULT OF THAT,
THOSE EXPERIENCES ARE
WHAT GAVE HIM HIS POWER.
( Kirito gasps )
HIS IMAGINATION. OF COURSE!
VOLO’S STRENGTH IS TIED
TO AN OLD FAMILY MOTTO
HE GREW UP WITH,
SO, IF HE BEATS SOMEONE STRONG,
HE BELIEVES
HE’LL GET STRONGER FROM IT.
Liena: WATCH OUT.
HE AIMS TO DRAW BLOOD TODAY
SO HE CAN WET HIS BLADE
AND GROW EVEN STRONGER.
( Kirito sighs )
( gasps )
Liena: I KNOW YOU CAN DO THIS.
I HAVE THE UTMOST FAITH IN YOU.
YOU ARE NOT
THE TYPE OF SWORDSMAN
WHO WOULD FALL SO EASILY TO HIM.
ALSO, THIS IS
THE PERFECT OPPORTUNITY
TO FULFILL YOUR PROMISE.
Kirito: WHAT PROMISE?
OH! YEAH,
I SAID I’D SHOW YOU
THE BEST SWORD SKILL I HAD.
Liena: THAT’S RIGHT,
SO SHOW IT TO ME HERE ON HIM.
Kirito: DONE.
YOU’LL SEE THE BEST ONE I KNOW.
( Liena chuckles )
Volo: SHALL WE START,
TRAINEE KIRITO?
YEAH.
Volo: ELITE DISCIPLE SERLUT,
WILL YOU SERVE
AS WITNESS TO THIS DUEL?
Liena: YES, OF COURSE.
ELITE DISCIPLE LEVANTEIN
VERSUS PRIMARY TRAINEE KIRITO.
THE VICTOR SHALL BE THE ONE
WHO LANDS THE FIRST STRIKE.
( crowd cheering )
Liena: LET IT BE KNOWN
THAT BOTH PARTIES HAVE AGREED
TO USE REAL SWORDS
IN THIS MATCH.
( crowd murmuring )
♪
♪ SHINY SWORD, MY DIAMOND ♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ IT’S TIME ♪
♪
( crowd gasp )
Humbert: OH, MY WORD! I DIDN’T
KNOW PAINTING SWORDS BLACK
WAS A CUSTOM IN THE BOONIES.
DID YOU, LORD RAIOS?
Raios: DON’T BE
SO INSENSITIVE, HUMBERT.
IT’S NOT THE POOR PAGE’S FAULT
HE’S TOO BUSY TO POLISH
THE FILTH FROM HIS SWORD.
( crowd laughs )
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Liena: MOUNTAIN-SPLITTING WAVE
OF THE HIGH-NORKIAN STYLE.
HE’S STARTING
WITH HIS BEST SKILL! ( grunts )
Kirito: THAT’S AVALANCHE,
A HEAVY, ONE-HIT THRUST...
BUT IT’S
THE HARD-CORE VERSION OF IT.
HIS IMAGINATION’S
BOOSTING ITS POWER.
DODGING’S NOT AN OPTION.
NO. I’M GONNA
HAVE TO BLOCK HIS STRIKE.
I GOT A PROMISE TO KEEP.
I HAVE TO COUNTER
WITH SOMETHING BIGGER,
LIKE THE FOUR-PART
VERTICAL SQUARE.
( deep breath)
( Volo yells )
( Kirito grunts )
( yells )
Liena: HE BLOCKED IT!
( Kirito grunting )
( Volo grunting )
Kirito: IF I CAN HOLD OUT...
I CAN STILL GET
MY FOURTH HIT IN!
( gasps )
HOLY CRAP, IS THAT
THE SOURCE OF HIS POWER?!
( all yelling )
HE’S PICTURING HIS ANCESTORS
BACKING HIM UP!
♪
( Liena gasps )
Kirito: I WON’T LOSE TO HIM.
NO WAY!
I CAN’T!
I’M NOT GONNA LET YOU BEAT ME!
♪
Volo: D-DID HIS SWORD JUST GROW?
( gasps )
( Kirito roaring )
( yells )
Azurica: THAT IS ENOUGH!
( Kirito gasps )
( Liena gasps )
Kirito: M-MS. AZURICA.
( footsteps )
Volo: IF SHE DECIDES THE DUEL
IS OVER, WE MUST OBEY HER.
Kirito: UM, OKAY.
BUT WHY, THOUGH?
Volo: YEARS AGO,
DURING THE FOUR EMPIRE
UNIFICATION TOURNAMENT,
SHE WAS THE FIRST SWORDSMAN
TO REPRESENT NORTH NORLANGARTH.
( Kirito gasps )
Volo: TRAINEE KIRITO’S
PUNISHMENT IS HEREBY FULFILLED!
NEXT TIME, TRY NOT
TO FLING MUD ONTO ANYONE.
YOU WERE LUCKY TODAY.
( Kirito gasps )
( crowd cheering )
( Eugeo laughs )
( Kirito chuckles )
( gasps )
IT’S BACK TO NORMAL.
Liena: I THOUGHT
YOU’D BEEN SLASHED.
Kirito: YEAH.
TALK ABOUT CLOSE, HUH?
Liena: ANYONE ELSE
WOULD HAVE SURRENDERED.
OH, YOU HOPELESS FOOL.
( sighs )
THAT SAID,
IT WAS A MAGNIFICENT FIGHT.
WELL DONE.
I AM FOREVER GRATEFUL.
ON THE ONE HAND,
I WISH I COULD’VE FOUGHT YOU,
BUT ON THE OTHER,
YOU DID KEEP YOUR PROMISE
AND SHOWED ME
WHAT YOU ARE CAPABLE OF.
NICELY DONE.
Kirito: BUT, UM, NOBODY WON.
IT WAS A DRAW.
Liena: IS ACHIEVING A DRAW
AGAINST THE FIRST SEAT
NOT GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU?
Kirito: UH, NO.
THAT’S NOT WHAT I MEANT.
Liena: I HOPE NOT. THE RESULT
WASN’T EVEN THE POINT.
SEEING YOU FIGHT WAS, ACTUALLY.
IT TAUGHT ME SOMETHING,
SOMETHING EXTREMELY IMPORTANT.
WE CAN TALK ABOUT IT BACK
AT MY PLACE WHILE WE CELEBRATE.
WE’LL INVITE EUGEO
AND LORD GOLGOROSSO, TOO.
( Kirito chuckles )
SURE!
( crowd cheering )
( Raios growls )
Azurica: HMM.
- ( no audible dialogue )
- ( cheering fades )
Liena: AS I WAS WATCHING
YOUR MATCH, IT HIT ME AGAIN.
YOUR AINCRAD STYLE
HAS LIMITLESS POSSIBILITIES.
AS FOR THE SERLUT STYLE, I ONCE
SAW IT AS A PRACTICAL SKILL,
BUT IT’S TOO STIFF.
Kirito: OH, COME ON.
DON’T GO THERE AGAIN.
I HAVEN’T BEATEN YOU
A SINGLE TIME SINCE I GOT HERE.
SERLUT STYLE’S ATTACKS
ARE SO DIVERSE.
IN MY BOOK,
THAT’S WHAT MAKES IT SO AMAZING.
( Liena sighs )
ITS HISTORY IS, TOO.
Kirito: HOW?
Liena: ONCE,
A DISTANT ANCESTOR OF MINE
ANGERED THE EMPEROR AT THE TIME,
AND, BECAUSE OF THAT,
THE SERLUT FAMILY WAS BANISHED
FROM THE OFFICIAL
HIGH NORKIA STYLE INDEFINITELY.
( Kirito gasps )
Liena: SO MY FAMILY IMPROVISED,
AND THEN, FROM THAT,
OUR NONTRADITIONAL STYLE
WAS DEVELOPED,
BECOMING THE SERLUT STYLE.
I DON’T RESENT IT BY ANY MEANS.
ON THE CONTRARY, I HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN PROUD OF OUR STYLE.
( sighs ) STILL...
I MAY HAVE RETAINED SOME DOUBTS
ABOUT ITS LEGITIMACY.
( Kirito gasps )
Liena: THESE TWO YEARS,
I COULDN’T BEAT VOLO,
NOT BECAUSE HE SPECIALIZED
IN A BETTER STYLE,
BUT BECAUSE
I FELT MINE WAS LESSER.
Kirito: LIENA.
Liena: YOU AND I, THOUGH,
WE BOTH HAVE
UNIQUE STYLES OF SWORDPLAY.
THE DIFFERENCE IS
YOU DON’T FEEL INFERIOR
TO THOSE TRAINED
IN MORE ORTHODOX STYLES.
AFTER WATCHING YOU
THIS PAST YEAR
AND SEEING HOW YOU FOUGHT
WITH VOLO IN TODAY’S DUEL,
TO BE HONEST, I THINK
I UNDERSTAND WHY YOU DON’T.
FOR ME,
KNOWING I’M THE SUCCESSOR
TO THE SERLUT STYLE FILLS ME
WITH GREAT PRIDE AND JOY.
THERE IS NO BETTER FEELING.
BECOMING YOUR MENTOR
IS A CLOSE SECOND, THOUGH.
( Kirito chuckles )
THANKS, LIENA.
AND NOW THAT YOU SAW
HOW I COUNTERED VOLO,
YOU SHOULDN’T HAVE ANY TROUBLE
BEATING HIM IN THE FINALS.
Liena: RIGHT.
♪
( Kirito gasps )
Raios: OH. WELL, WELL!
WHAT PERFECT TIMING!
I WAS HOPING I’D RUN INTO YOU,
AND HERE YOU ARE.
Kirito: WHAT DO YOU GUYS WANT?
Raios: WELL, NATURALLY
I WANTED TO COMMEND YOU
ON YOUR DAZZLING
PERFORMANCE EARLIER.
Humbert: TRUE. THOSE WERE
SOME VERY FLASHY-LOOKING SKILLS.
I’M CERTAIN YOU UNNERVED
FIRST SEAT LEVANTEIN
WITH YOUR DASHING THEATRICS.
( both laugh )
Kirito: WHAT ARE YOU,
PICKIN’ A FIGHT?
Raios: CERTAINLY NOT!
A NOBLEMAN WOULD NEVER DARE
ENGAGE IN UNCOUTH ACTIVITIES
WITH A COMMONER,
UNLESS IT’S GIVING HANDOUTS.
( both laugh )
Raios: TO PRAISE YOUR STUNT--
NO, TO HONOR YOUR BATTLE,
HERE IS A GIFT.
NO NEED TO THANK ME.
IT IS MY ONE CHARITABLE ACT
FOR THE DAY.
GOOD NIGHT, SIR KIRITO.
Humbert: "SIR" NOTHING!
♪
( Kirito gasps )
( gasping )
Kirito: IT STARTED OUT
AS AN EXPERIMENT.
THE ZEPHILIA IS A TYPE OF FLOWER
THAT DOESN’T BLOOM
ANYWHERE IN THE NORTHERN EMPIRE.
LIENA TOLD ME
THAT THEY WERE HER FAVORITE.
I TRIED TO MAKE ’EM BLOOM
USING MY IMAGINATION THEORY.
AND ALONG THE WAY
I STARTED IDENTIFYING
WITH THE FLOWERS,
’CAUSE I KNEW HOW HARD IT WAS,
TRYING TO STAY ALIVE
IN A FOREIGN PLACE.
HAVING BEEN CUT OFF
FROM THE REAL WORLD
AND ALL THE PEOPLE
I LOVED AND CARED FOR
MADE ME FEEL MORE AND MORE ALONE
AS TIME WENT ON HERE.
I SHARED THAT PAIN
WITH THESE FLOWERS.
♪
I’M SORRY.
( Kirito gasps )
( crying )
- Woman: HAVE FAITH.
- ( Kirito gasps )
Woman: BELIEVE IN THE STRENGTH
OF THE FLOWERS
YOU GREW IN THIS FOREIGN SOIL.
Kirito: WHO’S THERE?
Woman: BELIEVE IN YOURSELF, TOO,
FOR HELPING THEM GROW
AS WELL AS THEY HAVE.
Kirito: YEAH, BUT IT
DIDN’T MATTER IN THE END.
Woman: WORRY NOT.
THEIR ROOTS STILL CLING TO LIFE
WITHIN THE SOIL.
YOU SENSE IT, DO YOU NOT?
THE SACRED FLOWERS
IN THIS GARDEN
WANT TO SAVE THEIR FRIENDS.
THEIR ENERGY SHALL AID YOU.
Kirito: BUT HOW?
I DON’T KNOW
ANY OF THE SPELLS THAT CAN HELP.
YOU DO NOT NEED TO.
THE ARTS ARE ONLY TOOLS
TO HARNESS
AND REFINE THE MEANING,
OR WHAT YOU CALL
THE "MENTAL IMAGE."
USE YOUR HEART.
FEEL THE PRAYERS OF THE FLOWERS,
THE WAYS OF THE WORLD.
Kirito: FEEL THE PRAYERS
OF THE FLOWERS,
THE MEANING.
( breathing deeply )
( gasps )
♪
PLEASE, HELP ME.
I NEED YOU TO SHARE
SOME OF YOUR POWER.
IMAGINE THE FLOWERS’S LIFE FORCE
FLOWING THROUGH YOU
AND INTO THE ZEPHILIAS’S ROOTS.
♪
( gasps )
WHOEVER YOU ARE...
THANKS A LOT.
( crowd cheering )
( Liena yells )
( Volo yells )
♪
( wooden blades clacking )
( Liena gasps )
( grunts )
( Volo yells )
( Liena yells )
( yells )
( Volo gasps )
Azurica: MATCH OVER!
( crowd cheering )
( Eugeo laughs )
♪
( no audible dialogue )
Kirito: LIENA GRADUATED
FROM THE NORTH CENTORIA
SWORDCRAFT ACADEMY.
( chuckles )
SHE WAS THE TOP-RANKED
STUDENT THAT YEAR.
( Liena laughs )
Kirito: AFTER
OUR ADVANCEMENT EXAM,
EUGEO AND ME WERE RANKED
SEAT FIVE AND SIX
AND GOT PROMOTED
TO ELITE DISCIPLES.
Girl: ELITE DISCIPLE EUGEO,
I AM HERE TO REPORT.
THE ASSIGNED CLEANING
HAS BEEN COMPLETED!
THANKS, TIESE. GOOD WORK.
I DON’T HAVE
ANYTHING ELSE FOR YOU,
SO YOU’RE FREE TO GO.
OH, AND, UM...
( girl whimpers )
( Eugeo chuckles )
I’M SORRY, RONIE.
I DON’T KNOW HOW MANY TIMES
I’VE TOLD HIM TO BE BACK
BEFORE YOU FINISH CLEANING,
BUT HE NEVER LISTENS.
Ronie: IT’S FINE! I-I’LL JUST
WAIT UNTIL HE COMES BACK
SO I CAN MAKE MY REPORT.
Eugeo: YOU KNOW,
IF YOU REALLY WANT,
I CAN ALWAYS PUT IN A GOOD WORD
SO YOU CAN GET YOUR MENTOR
CHANGED TO SOMEONE ELSE.
YOU’RE GOING TO HAVE
A REALLY LONG YEAR
IF YOU SERVE UNDER HIM.
JUST A WARNING.
Ronie: OH, I-I DON’T MIND!
- Kirito: I KNEW IT!
- ( both gasp )
Kirito: YOU GUYS WERE TALKING
ABOUT ME BEHIND MY BACK.
( Ronie gasps )
UM, ELITE DISCIPLE KIRITO,
HERE’S MY REPORT.
CLEANING IS COMPLETE.
EVERYTHING IS SHINY
AND SPOTLESS.
Kirito: OH, OKAY. THANKS.
Eugeo: COME ON, KIRITO.
THESE TWO HAVE
A LOT ON THEIR PLATE,
SO PLEASE RESPECT THAT.
AT LEAST TRY TO GET BACK HERE
BEFORE THEY’RE DONE CLEANING.
AND COULD YOU TELL ME
WHY YOU’RE COMING IN
THROUGH THE WINDOW
ALL OF A SUDDEN?
Kirito: ’CAUSE IT’S
THE SHORTEST ROUTE
FROM EAST THIRD STREET.
IT’S WAY FASTER
THAN GOING THROUGH THE LOBBY.
KEEP THAT IN MIND,
’CAUSE ON DAYS
YOU’RE RUNNING LATE,
IT’S A LIFESAVER.
Girls: OH! RIGHT!
Eugeo: COULD YOU
NOT TEACH THEM THAT?
HANG ON. IF YOU’RE
COMING FROM EAST THIRD,
THEN THAT BAG IS FROM--
Kirito: HA! SO MUCH FOR MANNERS
WHEN YOUR STOMACH’S RUMBLING,
EH, EUGEO?
HERE.
( girls gasp )
Kirito: HERE. I BOUGHT EXTRA
SO YOU CAN SHARE SOME
WITH YOUR DORMMATES.
( girls laugh )
Ronie: THANK YOU SO MUCH,
ELITE DISCIPLE KIRITO!
Tiese: WE’LL HEAD BACK
AS FAST AS WE CAN
AND EAT THESE
BEFORE THEIR LIFE DECREASES!
WE’LL SEE YOU TOMORROW!
OOH! IT’S FULL OF HONEY PIES
FROM THE PRANCING DEER CAFÉ!
LET’S HURRY
BEFORE THEY GET COLD!
- Ronie: YEAH!
- Tiese: COME ON!
( Eugeo sighs )
( Kirito swallows )
WHAT’S UP?
Eugeo: OH, NOTHING MUCH, REALLY.
IT’S JUST I’M WONDERING
WHERE YOUR HEAD’S AT.
I HOPE YOU HAVEN’T GOTTEN
SO COMFORTABLE LATELY
THAT YOU’VE FORGOTTEN WHY WE
CAME HERE IN THE FIRST PLACE.
( Kirito chuckles )
LIKE I’D FORGET.
( swallows )
WE’RE CLOSER NOW THAN EVER.
Eugeo: MM-HMM.
ALMOST THERE.
♪
( singing in Japanese )
♪ THE IRIS TO YOU ♪